Based on actual events. And terrible decisions.
Roofman is a crime, comedy, drama film directed by Derek Cianfrance.
A former Army Ranger and struggling father turns to robbing McDonald’s restaurants by cutting holes in their roofs, earning him the nickname
"Roofman." After escaping prison, he secretly lives inside a Toys “R” Us for six months, surviving undetected while planning his next move.
But when he falls for a divorced mom drawn to his undeniable charm, his double life begins to unravel,
setting off a compelling and suspenseful game of cat and mouse as his past closes in.
Jeffrey Manchester, played by Channing Tatum.
Leigh Wainscott, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Pastor Ron, played by Ben Mendelsohn.
Steve, played by LaKeith Stanfield.
Michelle, played by Juno Temple.
Talena, played by Melonie Díaz.
Roofman is a 2025 American crime film directed by Derek Cianfrance.
It is based on the real-life spree robber Jeffrey Manchester, played by Channing
Tatum, who hid out in a toy store after escaping from prison.
The film also stars Kirsten Dunst, LaKeith Stanfield, Juno Temple, and
Peter Dinklage, with Ben Mendelsohn, Uzo Aduba, and Jimmy O.
Yang appearing in supporting roles.
Roofman had its world premiere at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 6, 2025 and was
theatrically released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on October 10, 2025.
It received positive reviews from critics and grossed $34 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of based on true story, true crime, toy
store, escaped prisoner, charlotte, north carolina.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and intense.